A read me file can technically be written in any file format.
فنيًا يمكن كتابة ملف read me بأي تنسيق ملف.
You can make your read me web page,
يمكنك عمل صفحة ويب read me،
a simple text file or even a made up format if you wanted to.
أو ملف نصي أو حتى تنسيق منظّم إذا أردت.
For this lesson,
بالنسبة لهذا الدرس،
you'll be generating your read me using language known as markdown.
سننشئ ملف read me باستخدام اللغة المعروفة markdown.
Markdown let's you generate well formatted read mes
تتيح لك لغة markdown إنشاء ملفات read mes منسّقة جيدًا
by translating them into HTML.
عن طريق ترجمتها إلى HTML.
Sites that you may use often as a developer, such as GitHub,
تستخدم جميع المواقع التي تستخدمها في كثير من الأحيان كمطور مثل GitHub
Stack Overflow, Slack, and even Reddit, all use versions of markdown for
وموقع Stack Overflow وحتى Reddit، إصدارات لغة markdown
quick and easy formating of your content.
من أجل تسريع وتسهيل تنسيق المحتوى.
One of the main advantages to using markdown is that we can make read-mes
أحد المزايا الرئيسية لاستخدام لغة markdown هو أنه يمكننا إنشاء ملفات read-mes
that are easy to skim through.
التي من السهل الاستخلاص من خلالها.
Take a look at these two recipes.
ألقِ نظرة على هاتين الوصفتين.
Both of these have the same information.
يحتوي كلاهما على نفس المعلومات.
But without even needing to read the contents of each,
ولكن دون الحاجة إلى قراءة المحتويات في كلاهما.
which one would you rather follow?
أي واحدة منهما تفضل أن تتبعها؟
The recipe on the right is formatted in a way that makes it
تم تنسيق الوصفة الموجودة على اليمن
easy to skim through.
بطريقة تجعلها سهلة للاستخلاص من خلالها.
When writing read-mes, take advantage of the awesome features markdown gives you
عند كتابة ملفات، استفد من الميزات الرائعة للغة markdown التي تعطيك إياها
to make sure they are easily readable.
للتأكد من أنها يمكن قراءتها بسهولة.
You'll practice writing markdown in the next few nodes, but
ستمارس كتابة لغة markdown في العقد القليلة المقبلة،
first I'll be giving you a quick guide to markdown syntax.
لكن أولًا سأعطيك دليلًا سريعًا لبناء جملة لغة markdown.